[{"content": ": Mr Murali.", "entities": [[2, 11, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": ": Mr Speaker, I am obliged to the Leader of the House for moving the Motion.", "entities": [[69, 75, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "The first point is really replacing \"affirms\" with \"recognises\", to be more precise. And that is to state the fact that from the outset, from Singapore's Independence, fairness, access and independence are cornerstones of the Singapore justice system.", "entities": [[142, 151, "NORP"], [226, 250, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "And the next point, Sir, it is in relation to the usage of the word \"affirms\". And this is really to state as a matter of truth, that the Government has been continually putting in the effort since Independence to build a fair and just society, to remedy any shortcoming to enhance justice for all regardless of race, language, religion, economic means or social status. So, I added the words \"race, language, religion\" and I do not think that should be controversial.", "entities": [[138, 148, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "I have proposed to delete \"including facilitating a review\" of the justice system. Let me explain why.Â This is to leave this Motion in broad terms so that at the end of the day, it is an affirmation that the Government would continue to remedy any shortcoming that is brought up, and to allow the conversation to happen in this House about what further steps need to be taken.", "entities": [[126, 132, "LAW"], [209, 219, "ORG"], [329, 334, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "One should realise this. At the end of the day, the buck stops with this House. It is this House that has to make the political decisions to pass legislation, to move amendments to the Constitution in relation to the justice system. So, the buck must stop here and this Motion reflects that reality. I do not think anything is taken away with the amendments that I propose.", "entities": [[185, 197, "LAW"], [270, 276, "LAW"], [73, 78, "ORG"], [91, 96, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Sir, I am clear in my mind where the PAP Government stands on this. The raison d'etre of the PAP is to build a fair and just society, founded on justice and equality for all people, especially the disadvantaged. This applies in and out of Court.", "entities": [[93, 96, "NORP"], [37, 51, "NORP"], [239, 244, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Just a few days ago, Miss Lim,Â a daughter of a man who was on his deathbed approached me. She was served with a Stay-Home Notice or SHN, and she was extremely concerned that she would not be able to see her father at the deathbed because she had to serve the SHN. Within three hours, she was able to see her father in the hospital. Which other country would be able to do this and this was way after office hours?", "entities": [[21, 29, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Sir, let us not forget, while we wish to improve the system, we have every reason to be proud of the justice system and, in fact, the Government system that we have in place today. This is not the time to throw the baby out with the bathwater. And I believe my hon friends from Workers' Party across the aisle would also hold true to the same values. With that, I beg to move.", "entities": [[278, 292, "NORP"]]}, {"content": ": There are five amendments proposed by Mr Murali Pillai. These are:", "entities": [[40, 56, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "(2) In line 3, to delete 'calls on the Government to recognise' and insert 'affirms the Government's continuous efforts since Independence to build a fair and just society';", "entities": [[39, 49, "ORG"], [88, 98, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ": Mr Speaker, I believe Ms Sylvia Lim may have been asking whether she could speak on the vote to amend the Motion. Is that correct, Ms Lim? Or are you asking to speak on the vote on the Motion, as amended?", "entities": [[2, 12, "PERSON"], [24, 37, "PERSON"], [133, 139, "PERSON"], [108, 114, "LAW"], [187, 193, "LAW"]]}, {"content": ": Mr Speaker, I would like your ruling whether I am entitled to a right of reply as the mover of the original Motion.", "entities": [[110, 116, "LAW"]]}, {"content": ": The amendments have been agreed to.Â The original Motion, as amended, is now before the House.", "entities": [[52, 58, "LAW"], [90, 95, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ": After Ms Indranee Rajah, you will wrap up. You will be wrapping up the discussion. Ms Indranee Rajah.", "entities": [[8, 25, "PERSON"], [85, 102, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": ": Thank you, Mr Speaker. Mr Speaker, when Ms Sylvia Lim moved this Motion, she said that she was not saying that the system is broken but it can be improved. She also said that today's Motion is not about tearing down the system or discouraging those who work in law enforcement, the AGC or the Courts; far from it, it is about a desire to raise the system to the next level, which indeed I think is something that we can all agree on.", "entities": [[42, 55, "PERSON"], [67, 73, "LAW"], [185, 191, "LAW"], [284, 287, "ORG"], [295, 301, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The Workers' Party had put forward some suggestions. These have been debated. I would like in my speech to address the suggestions that were put forward by Mr Pritam Singh, the Leader of the Opposition, specifically with regard to decoupling the function of the Attorney-General and the function of the Public Prosecutor.", "entities": [[4, 18, "NORP"], [156, 171, "PERSON"], [191, 201, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Singh made three points. But actually, the second two points are really premised on the first.Â So, let me deal with the first one.", "entities": [[0, 8, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "His first point was that there is, allegedly, a weakness in our prosecutorial structure and that arises from the two roles of the AG: one being his role as the Government's legal advisor and the other being the role as a Public Prosecutor.Â In the first, he takes charge of three areasÂ â€“ legislation, international affairs and civil matters. In the second, as the Public Prosecutor, he has to prosecute without fear or favour.", "entities": [[160, 170, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The essence of Mr Singh's argument is that there is a conflict, an inherent conflict in these two roles. And he articulated it in this form, that as the Government's legal advisor, the Attorney-General's duty is to protect the interests of the Government and as the Public Prosecutor, it is to represent the public and prosecute without fear or favour.", "entities": [[15, 23, "PERSON"], [153, 163, "ORG"], [244, 254, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ": Yes, Ms Sylvia Lim.", "entities": [[7, 20, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "In addressing this, he also mentioned that Ms Sylvia Lim had raised this point previously. Indeed, she had, but not quite in the same way.", "entities": [[43, 56, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "So, what I want to do is firstly, address how Ms Sylvia Lim articulated it and then, I will go on to address how Mr Singh articulated it. To be fair, they both want to reach the same point, which is that there is a conflict so you should decouple them. But actually, the argument has evolved a little bit.", "entities": [[46, 59, "PERSON"], [113, 121, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Let me first start off with how Ms Sylvia Lim first put it. She put it in this way: \"in order to further strengthen the system and shore up the independence of the Public Prosecutor\", we should \"consider splitting the two roles...to reside in two different offices, so that the person who is the Public Prosecutor or PP, is not the same person taking the Government's instructions in non-criminal matters. I believe this separation exists in other countries to enhance the independence of the PP's office.\"", "entities": [[32, 45, "PERSON"], [355, 365, "ORG"], [493, 504, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "So, the first point that she made was that, you must decouple it so that the person, who is the PP, is not the same person taking the Government's instructions in non-criminal matters. But thisÂ argument is not correct because in non-criminal matters the Attorney-General advises the Government, the Government is his client. And similar to private sector matters, he takes in instructions on matters which are within the Government's purview.", "entities": [[134, 144, "ORG"], [284, 294, "ORG"], [300, 310, "ORG"], [422, 432, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "But in criminal matters, the Attorney-General decides whether to prosecute. The Executive and the Cabinet have no say in that.", "entities": [[98, 105, "ORG"], [80, 89, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "So, there is no issue with the same person in both roles because the system ensures that in his PP role, the AG acts independently. And the thrust of that argument that Ms Sylvia Lim originally made was that, you are taking the Government's instructions. You take the Government's instructions on the civil matters, on the other matters, but not when it comes to the decision to prosecute.", "entities": [[169, 182, "PERSON"], [228, 238, "ORG"], [268, 278, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "In responding to that, then Senior Minister of State Edwin Tong also pointed out that the reason why the role is separate in other countries is because in those countries where the roles are separate â€“ in countries such as UK, Canada, Australia, New Zealand â€“ the Attorney-General holds political office. He is a political office holder or he sits in Cabinet. There is therefore the question of being subject to political pressures and the separation of the role of the Attorney-General from the public prosecutor in those jurisdictions has to be looked at in that context because he is subject to political pressure. Whereas hereÂ â€“ and I will go on to discuss that in a bit more detail later â€“ our situation is different because our Constitution has safeguards in that our AGÂ does not hold political office. The constitutional safeguards ensure that he is protected from such political pressures, and it allows him to discharge both his roles as PP and the Government's legal advisor without fear or favour.", "entities": [[28, 63, "PERSON"], [225, 227, "GPE"], [229, 235, "GPE"], [237, 246, "GPE"], [248, 259, "GPE"], [355, 362, "ORG"], [743, 755, "LAW"], [968, 978, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "I come back to Mr Singh's argument today. Previously, the argument was you should do it the same way as other countries becauseÂ of independence. And then, of course, it was pointed out that in other countries, because the AG is a political office holder, that is why you have to separate it.", "entities": [[15, 23, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "So, today, the argument is that as the Government's legal advisor, the AG's duty is to protect the interests of the Government. Well, yes and no.", "entities": [[39, 49, "ORG"], [116, 126, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Because as Mr Singh pointed out, as the Government's legal advisor, the AG takes charge of legislation.Â So, when he protects the Government's interest in legislation, that has nothing to do with his prosecutorial function.", "entities": [[11, 19, "PERSON"], [40, 50, "ORG"], [130, 140, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "His other role as advisor is international affairs. When he is advising the Government on international affairs, that has nothing to do with prosecution.", "entities": [[76, 86, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The third oneÂ â€“ civil matters. When he is advising the Government on civil matters, that has nothing to do with his role as a prosecutor.", "entities": [[58, 68, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The track record shows that the Attorney-General hasÂ prosecuted high level people before, without fear or favour. This includes, for example, the prosecution of Mr Ng Boon Gay, the former director of the CNB; the prosecution of Mr Peter Lim, the former SCDF Commissioner; and more recently, the charges against Mr Pek Lian Guan, CEO and Executive Director of Tiong Seng Holdings, and Pay Teow Heng, Director of Tiong Seng Contractors (Private) Limited.", "entities": [[162, 176, "PERSON"], [205, 208, "ORG"], [229, 241, "PERSON"], [254, 258, "ORG"], [312, 328, "PERSON"], [360, 379, "ORG"], [385, 398, "PERSON"], [412, 452, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Singh then raised a couple of examples of where there may be such conflict. And he talked about the difficulty the AG may have in prosecuting Government-linked companies, for example.Â But again, that is not the case because we have had no difficulty doing that.", "entities": [[0, 8, "PERSON"], [145, 155, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "In 2017, seven former officers of ST Marine who had been charged were convicted for giving corrupt payments to secure business and/or for other offences. These officers included former Presidents of ST Marine See Leong Teck and Chang Cheow Teck. ST Marine is a subsidiary of ST Engineering, which is in turn, majority-owned by Temasek Holdings, which is a Government-linked company.", "entities": [[34, 43, "ORG"], [199, 208, "ORG"], [209, 223, "PERSON"], [228, 244, "PERSON"], [246, 255, "ORG"], [275, 289, "ORG"], [327, 343, "ORG"], [356, 366, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "So, we have had no issue with prosecuting anybody, whether Government-linked or not, provided the PP sees that there is a case on the face of it to bring charges.", "entities": [[59, 69, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Then, Mr Singh went on to say that it would be difficult, for example, if in the case of â€“ it is a hypothetical example, not a current one â€“ a future government, where the Prime Minister and the AG may be very chummy and therefore the Attorney-General or the PP may not wish to bring a prosecution, either against the Prime Minister if there was an offence committed or somebody close, that thereby, he may have a desire to keep his job for favours or simply because the hypothetical alleged future Prime Minister and the AG are cronies.", "entities": [[6, 14, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Sir, section 22G of the Constitution provides that the Director of CPIB can go to the President if the Prime Minister refuses to proceed with a corruption investigation. The Constitution has many checks and balances. And it envisages that if such a situation may happen where the Prime Minister does not act in accordance with his duty, there is a check, there is a balance, and there is an avenue where corruption and other offences can be prosecuted.", "entities": [[67, 71, "ORG"], [174, 186, "LAW"], [24, 36, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "Mr Singh did point out that in other countries and he named two. He did not name them, but we know who they are. He said that in both these countries that prominent cases of the Attorney-General being subject to political pressure. And that is precisely the point.", "entities": [[0, 8, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Our system protects the Attorney-General from being subject to political pressure. First, with the appointment of the AG. The AG is appointed by the President on the advice of the Prime Minister. But the Prime Minister cannot do it just as a whim. The Prime Minister does it in consultation with the Chief Justice, in consultation with the incumbent Attorney-General and the Chairman of the Public Service Commission.", "entities": [[391, 416, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Singh then went on to say he had two suggestions for improvements, but the improvements are premised on being able to make out that there is a case that there was a conflict. And I have addressed why there is no conflict.", "entities": [[0, 8, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "But there is one point I want to address, which is securityÂ of tenure. Because I think the point that Mr Singh will likely make is that, well, you have all these safeguards, but if you have a relatively short term of tenure, then that sort of takes away from the ability to be independent.", "entities": [[103, 111, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "But actually, that is not the case either. There is no general rule for tenure. Some countries have a fixed tenure for their Attorneys-General, and some do not. Officers in charge of prosecutions in England and Wales, Australia, New Zealand and Hong Kong have no security of tenure and typically serve predetermined terms which may be renewable.", "entities": [[199, 206, "GPE"], [211, 216, "GPE"], [218, 227, "GPE"], [229, 240, "GPE"], [245, 254, "GPE"]]}, {"content": "And in the US, there is no security of tenure at all. In the words of one of their former Attorney-Generals who was asked to resign, he said, \"I serve at the pleasure of the President. I've understood that from the day I took the job\".", "entities": [[11, 13, "GPE"]]}, {"content": "So, what is more important is the constitutional safeguards against removal, and those we have in Singapore.", "entities": [[98, 107, "NORP"]]}, {"content": "The third point that Mr Singh made was that he suggested that the system eschews the appointment of ex-Member of Parliament as a Public Prosecutor. And he did say that such an individual can be considered for the role of Government legal advisor. That too is a little bit different from the position advanced by Ms Sylvia Lim before. Because Ms Sylvia Lim before when she raised this point, talked about not having an ex-Member of Parliament, or MP, as the Attorney-General. But shifted slightly â€“ now, it has just become only Public Prosecutor.", "entities": [[21, 29, "PERSON"], [113, 123, "ORG"], [221, 231, "ORG"], [312, 325, "PERSON"], [342, 355, "PERSON"], [431, 441, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The reason given by Mr Singh was this. He said firstly it would be natural for a former elected MP to have imbibed the political views of the party he or she used to represent. Even if the Public Prosecutor who was previously an MP does his or her sincere best to be objective, they cannot help but be a product of their previous beliefs, which they perhaps still hold. As a Public Prosecutor who was an MP of a political party and steeped in the party's ideology for years, he is likely to hold certain beliefs and approach things in certain ways.", "entities": [[20, 28, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "On the face of it, yes, it sounds a little bit worrying. But let us ask ourselves, what does that actually mean? What are the political views of the party that Mr Hri Kumar used to be in, for example.", "entities": [[160, 172, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Well, one of the views is we believe in meritocracy. As a member of the PAP, we believe in meritocracy. We believe in integrity. We believe in not having a corrupt system. We believe in access of justice. I am not sure how this would affect his prosecutorial functions. We also believe in a green and sustainable Singapore. I am not sure how that would affect his prosecutorial functions as well. I mean, what is it about the beliefs of the PAP that would somehow affect his prosecutorial functions? Nothing.", "entities": [[72, 75, "NORP"], [441, 444, "NORP"]]}, {"content": "Mr Singh did point out that appearances are important, he referred to how in this case, it was mentioned that the Attorney-General Mr Lucien Wong was not involved in any prosecutorial decisions regarding Ms Parti Liyani and thatÂ he would recuse himself from any on-going review of the case. As Minister Shanmugam explained, the earlier part of the prosecution, Mr WongÂ had nothing to do with it at all. That was dealt with at a different level. And since the matter has surfaced, he has recused himself very properly.", "entities": [[0, 8, "PERSON"], [131, 145, "PERSON"], [204, 219, "PERSON"], [295, 313, "PERSON"], [362, 369, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "So, I believe, Mr Speaker, I have addressed the points raised by Mr Singh. I just would conclude by saying that it seems that there is much in common. There are some differences in terms of the approach towards the Motion which Mr Murali's amendment addresses. I therefore support the amended Motion.", "entities": [[65, 73, "PERSON"], [228, 237, "PERSON"], [293, 299, "LAW"]]}, {"content": ": Mr Singh.", "entities": [[2, 10, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": ":Â Thank you, Mr Speaker.Â The first, with regard to a general point that the Leader makes about conflict. I will make the point that I do not believe the Leader's answers have squarely addressed the reality of possible conflict between the Attorney-General in his role as Government legal adviser on the one hand and public prosecutor on the other. I still take the view that the conflict is possible and that is the basis of the suggestion that I put in my speech.", "entities": [[273, 283, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "I will give an example. I gave two examples: one was with regard to that Government-linked company, which I hypothesised. Now, let me try and take it to some specifics. There is an old article, 23 December 1997. It is an opinion piece by an individual who would later become the Attorney-GeneralÂ in Singapore, Mr Walter Woon. And he talked about malfeasance, a corruption scandal involving Keppel again, but not the latest deferred prosecution agreement that was entered into byÂ â€”", "entities": [[73, 83, "ORG"], [194, 210, "DATE"], [311, 325, "PERSON"], [391, 397, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ": Mr Singh, you are raising a point of clarification?", "entities": [[2, 10, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": ": Yes, I am.Â Not the deferred prosecution agreement between Brazil, the US and Singapore, but a similar scandal that occurred previously. And there, what Mr WoonÂ really says is the Attorney-General decides to go after the company, but then does not prosecute the individuals. And so, the situation is the company can accept the fine, but the individuals who later may benefit because of these bribes that were given â€“ they benefit through the fact that the company will give out more bonuses to them, for example.", "entities": [[61, 67, "GPE"], [73, 75, "GPE"], [80, 89, "GPE"], [155, 162, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "So, the question, of course, is do we have a situation where we can tell ourselves, \"Look, there is no prospect, no implicit bias here\". Is there a system we can consider of conceive of, which can reduce that prospect in the public perception? And this is where I feel a division of the roles actually may be more helpful to the Government. That is the first point.", "entities": [[329, 339, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The second point is with regard to security of tenure. I hear what the Leader is saying. I take the point. Even in our own experience in Singapore, we have had Attorney-Generals who have served for a long period of time, and others just two years. And my point really is, it would serve the Government well, if the term was at least, for example, five years. I can agree with the suggestion that Mr Walter Woon made because it heightens the prospect of independence in the eyes of the public that this individual was not removed for reasons which the public may start imagining â€“ which may or may not be true.", "entities": [[137, 146, "NORP"], [291, 301, "ORG"], [347, 357, "DATE"], [396, 410, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "To that end, I did consider whether this position is supposed to be for all time. Let us say, if an MP steps down in 2020, does it mean that he cannot take on the appointment as AG forever and ever? Could there be some scope to consider at least a moratorium period or a garden leave period? I did consider that. So, if there is a question of some concession or some coming together as the Leader suggested in her wrapping-up paragraph and that the positions between the Government and Opposition are not so far apart, perhaps the Government can consider some of the proposals in that light to see how we can end up with a better legal system.", "entities": [[117, 121, "DATE"], [471, 481, "ORG"], [486, 496, "ORG"], [531, 541, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ":Â I thank the Leader of the Opposition for his clarifications. He raised three. Let me deal with them in turn. With respect to the first one, he mentioned a concern where he articulated that you go after the company and not the individuals. It so happens that in this case, I think if he is referring to the previous case of Keppel O&M, as I had explained in a previous answer in Parliament, that a conditional warning was issued to the company with various penalties. And in that case I had also explained that with respect to the individuals, evidence still needed to be gathered and that it was not a case where somebody had got off or not got off. But rather, it was a case where the Public Prosecutor was facing challenges in terms of getting the evidence. In fact, those investigations still continue. The Attorney-General's office or the Public Prosecutor's office has requested further information and it is still pending. That is out of our hands.", "entities": [[29, 39, "ORG"], [326, 336, "ORG"], [381, 391, "ORG"], [813, 838, "ORG"], [846, 872, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "But and this is a big \"but\", if that person in any way shows that he or she is not acting in accordance with the duties, then appropriate action would have to be taken. That is how we can make sure that our system remains independent, remains strong and remains robust. But I welcome the debate because I understand what drives it, which is the desire to improve the system and to make one better for Singapore. I thank the Leader of the Opposition for his suggestions.", "entities": [[401, 410, "NORP"], [438, 448, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ":Â Thank you, Mr Speaker. On the first point, this is just as a matter of clarification with the Leader. I do not mean to be argumentative, but I am not referring to the latest Keppel infraction. In 1997, there was another case where Keppel Corp, I do not know the formalÂ legal entity that was involved in this, it does not say Keppel O&M, so I am just reading off what it is. It says, \"Keppel Corp faced 17 charges of bribery, a total of $8.3 million was paid to the Repair and Technical Manager of a British subsidiary of Exxon\" and Keppel got contracts to repair 17 of their tankers. \"The statement of facts extended to the court revealed that this had been done with the knowledge and approval of senior Keppel executives and some directors\", \"the prosecution chose to proceed only with three of the charges. KeppelÂ pleaded guilty, which meant that it admitted to the statement of facts without qualification\", \"the district judge fined Keppel the maximum $100,000 on each of the charges and a total of $300,000, and that was the end of the matter\".", "entities": [[177, 183, "ORG"], [199, 203, "DATE"], [234, 245, "ORG"], [329, 339, "ORG"], [388, 399, "ORG"], [525, 530, "ORG"], [536, 542, "ORG"], [709, 715, "ORG"], [814, 820, "ORG"], [943, 949, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "So, I think the point that is being made in this particular case is, the question on the minds of the public in the context of a public prosecutor that also performs the role of the Government legal advisor is, was that discretion, the prosecutorial discretion exercised appropriately? And I think this is where as the Leader suggests, she understands where the thrust of some of our concerns are coming from. These are the sort of situations which we feel may compromise in the public eye, rightly or wrongly, the independence of the AG.", "entities": [[182, 192, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ":Â Mr Speaker, Sir, I do not have the facts with respect to the 1997 case. But the point is that there does not seem to be anything in what Mr Singh has said which indicates why further action was not taken. We do not know at this point of time and I do not wish to speculate.", "entities": [[64, 68, "DATE"], [140, 148, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "I think where the Leader of the Opposition is coming from is that whatever the case in the prosecution, people must feel satisfied that the prosecutor in exercising his functions and duties, has done so properly. And I have given an example of how not in 1997 but many years down the line, where it is a case of the company and potential liability for individuals, company was pursued and the case against individuals is still open.", "entities": [[32, 42, "ORG"], [255, 259, "DATE"]]}, {"content": ": Ms Sylvia Lim. Would you be wrapping up?", "entities": [[2, 15, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": ":Â Mr Speaker, first, let me thank all Members who spoke on the Motion. Everyone who has spoken accepts that fairness, access and independence are cornerstones of our justice system. Let me summarise the Workers' Party's position first.", "entities": [[64, 70, "LAW"], [204, 220, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "In respect of fairness, the Leader of the Opposition has highlighted shortcomings in relation to the prosecution's duty of disclosure to the defence and how prosecutors have fallen short of these duties, as flagged", "entities": [[42, 52, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "by recent judgments from the Court of Appeal.", "entities": [[29, 44, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The unfairness faced by the poor was highlighted by MP for Sengkang Ms He Ting RuÂ and myself. We have described how a lack of resources can unfairly impact households who are faced with charges for offences, even minor ones. This is a major societal issue that if unaddressed could worsen the class divide and entrench inter-generational poverty.", "entities": [[59, 67, "GPE"], [68, 81, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Fairness is also an issue for those not comfortable in the English language, when it comes to statement recording by law enforcement. For this, I have suggested recording statements documented in other languages. Ms He raised the unfairness faced by those who are wrongly accused and suffered damage and harm. She argued that there should be recourse to compensation, balanced with the need for effective law enforcement in prosecutions.", "entities": [[213, 218, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "As far as access to justice is concerned, Ms He and Mr Gerald Giam, MP for Aljunied, have acknowledged the existence of legal aid schemes but pointed out that enhancements are due. For instance, criminal legal aid provided in non-capital cases should be entrenched in statute and not left as a Law Society initiative albeit co-funded by the Government.", "entities": [[42, 47, "PERSON"], [52, 66, "PERSON"], [75, 83, "GPE"], [294, 305, "ORG"], [341, 351, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Giam has particularly highlighted the disadvantages faced by migrant workers, whether it is crime victims or accused persons.", "entities": [[0, 7, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "On the right to consult a lawyer when arrested, Ms He pointed out that this was a constitutional right and a review is needed to ascertain if it is functioning optimally, balancing the interests of law enforcement and the accused.", "entities": [[48, 53, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "As regard to the third cornerstone of independence, several of my Party colleagues touched on this. MP for Hougang Mr Dennis Tan was concerned about judicial officers at the State Courts and how their independence could be enhanced. He suggested the State Court Judges should not be subject to rotation in and out of the Executive Government, and this could be assured by setting up a separate judicial service.", "entities": [[107, 114, "GPE"], [115, 128, "PERSON"], [174, 186, "ORG"], [250, 261, "ORG"], [331, 341, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "He also asked if the criteria for the appointment of State Court Judges should be raised to a higher threshold of seniority.", "entities": [[53, 64, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "The Leader of the Opposition Mr Pritam Singh proposed that the Attorney-General's office be subject to structural change to enhance its independence by decoupling the rules of public prosecutor and the Government legal advisor, so that they are held by different people. He also proposed a longer contractual period of five years for appointees to the post of AG and that any future nominee should have experience in criminal practice either as a judge, prosecutor or defence counsel.", "entities": [[29, 44, "PERSON"], [63, 88, "ORG"], [202, 212, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Another Aljuined MP Mr Leon Perera raised the need for additional independent checks on the actions of public bodies through the office of an ombudsman. I have also suggested that it is prudent to do a review on whether there is any institutional sub-culture that inadvertently results in discriminatory outcomes between the rich and poor. If such a sub-culture exists, steps should be taken to eradicate it.", "entities": [[8, 16, "GPE"], [20, 34, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Finally, Sengkang MP Assoc Prof Jamus Lim reminded us that strengthening the rule of law carries an economic imperative and is in the national interest.", "entities": [[9, 17, "GPE"], [21, 41, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Several Members gave different perspectives. Mr Xie Yao Quan praised our criminal justice system and said we should not tar everyone with the same brush. His point was that we should not be critical of all who work in the criminal justice system. And, of course, that was not my intention, as I pointed out that there are many public-spirited professionals in law enforcement, prosecution and the Courts, who take their mission seriously.", "entities": [[45, 60, "PERSON"], [397, 403, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Vikram Nair supported the spirit behind my Motion. He agreed with the principle of criminal law reform and spoke of the reforms legislated in the CPC in 2010. He also said that there could be greater access to counsel by accused persons at an earlier stageÂ and he agreed with the idea of a public defender's office. He said that my points on the plight of the poor, improvement of processes of law enforcement agencies and support of crime victims were things that could be looked into. I thank him for that.", "entities": [[0, 14, "PERSON"], [46, 52, "LAW"], [149, 153, "ORG"], [156, 160, "DATE"]]}, {"content": "I also think Mr Leong Mun Wai forÂ supporting the original Motion.", "entities": [[13, 29, "PERSON"], [59, 65, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "Ms Rahayu Mahzam reiterated points made by Minister Shanmugam in his Statement on Ms Parti Liyani's case. She said that unfairness is not pervasive and that processes and channels for help exist in our system. However, she agreed that our systems are not perfect and that we should work on our shortcomings and remedy them. If not, we were planting the seeds of doubt and eroding trust in the system.Â I thank her for saying those things.", "entities": [[0, 16, "PERSON"], [43, 61, "PERSON"], [82, 97, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Mr Louis Ng raised concerns about the timeline to implement video recording and on translation of statements.", "entities": [[0, 11, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Mr Murali Pillai gave us a lecture on the separation of government powers. He also shared his experiences working within the system.", "entities": [[0, 16, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "As for government responses, I am glad that Minister Shanmugam has recognised several issues that we have raised. He said that on many issues, we were on the same page, pushing at an open door. He said we were setting out positions of principle and he did not object to them, but that the front bench needed to think about the implementation.", "entities": [[44, 62, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "He said that on a few points, things are already moving. On other things, he said the Government would not be implementing them. He agreed that the poor do face bigger challenges in paying fines for regulatory offences and the potential snow-balling effect. He felt this was a complex issue that required the involvement of many agencies. He agreed that instalment payments could be allowed and that he has given directions to look into this.", "entities": [[86, 96, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "The Minister for the said that the Government is at ad idem with MP Pritam Singh and that the Government is consulting stakeholders on the codifying of common law case disclosure requirements. On legal aid for the poor, the Minister agreed with the principle, but felt that we should proceed cautiously in view of the experience in other countries. Nevertheless, he said that the Government was not fully satisfied with the current system and was looking into the feasibility of setting up a public defender's office.", "entities": [[35, 45, "LAW"], [65, 80, "PERSON"], [94, 104, "LAW"], [380, 390, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "On compensation for miscarriages of justice, the Minister felt that only vexatious cases deserved compensation. We ask the Government keep an open mind on this, as there could be other cases deserving of compensation.", "entities": [[123, 133, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "Minister Edwin Tong talked about the ombudsman and rejected our suggestion. He pointed out that the Government was more concerned with overall outcomes. Minister of State Gan Siow Huang highlighted the efforts made by the Government to support migrant workers in Singapore.", "entities": [[0, 19, "PERSON"], [153, 185, "PERSON"], [263, 272, "NORP"], [100, 110, "ORG"], [222, 232, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Mr Speaker, since we filed the Motion, many members of the public have reached out to us. They have shared with us their own experiences of being crime victims or suspects or having family members being subject to such experiences.", "entities": [[31, 37, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "Questions raised by the public include the following: where is the justice when someone is wrongly accused and had to endure humiliation in investigations, only to be acquitted?Â Does the prosecution aim to win cases at all costs?Â Do we treat migrant workers fairly or as modern-day slaves?Â How is it that the weaknesses in Parti Liyani's case were not picked up by law enforcement, the Prosecution and the trial Judge? How neutral are these agencies, they asked.", "entities": [[326, 338, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Mr Speaker, even if the Government and the ruling Party are not convinced that the system has shortcomings, the fact that the public is asking such questions should not be ignored. It is sad that after all the points made today on where improvements can be made or, in fact, are due, the Government does not even accept that the system has any shortcomings. I believe this is an opportunity to review the justice system with an open mind.", "entities": [[24, 34, "ORG"], [43, 55, "NORP"], [288, 298, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Sir, by filing this Motion, the Workers' Party is not motivated by a desire for heads to roll in the Parti Liyani case. What we hope to achieve is a strengthening of the system so that it is built to last for the future.", "entities": [[20, 26, "LAW"], [32, 46, "NORP"], [101, 113, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "To conclude, I would just like to summarise that we cannot accept the amendments proposed because they imply that there are no shortcomings in the system and that there will be no review of the system.Â As these are key aspects of our original Motion, we are unable to support the amended Motion.", "entities": [[244, 250, "LAW"], [289, 295, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "Any clarifications? Minister Shanmugam.", "entities": [[20, 38, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "I just want to clarify that what I had said is that we are looking at putting in statutory form the disclosure requirements. I think Ms Sylvia Lim said or attributed to me a different formulation. So, I just want to be clear.", "entities": [[133, 146, "PERSON"]]}, {"content": "Mr Speaker, Sir, I just want to clarify a comment made by the hon Member Ms Sylvia Lim on the purport of the amendment. She appears to have understood my amendments as suggesting that the Government does not admit that there was any shortcoming in the past.", "entities": [[73, 86, "PERSON"], [188, 198, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "That was not my intent. In fact, if anything, Mr Speaker, the point I was stressing in my speech was that there were shortcomings in the past. But the point is, the Government continues to expend effort to improve the system and to ensure there is justice for all.", "entities": [[165, 175, "ORG"]]}, {"content": ": Any final clarifications before midnight?Â The original Motion, as amended, is now", "entities": [[58, 64, "LAW"]]}, {"content": "before the House.", "entities": [[11, 16, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "f the Opposition.", "entities": [[6, 16, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "Workers' Party Members of Parliament would like to have our dissent recorded. Thank you.", "entities": [[0, 14, "NORP"]]}, {"content": "hank you very much for bearing with us and, thankfully, finishing before midnight. I just want to register my thanks to our staff in Parliament, the security staff and so on, and especially our interpreters, for supporting us up to this point. [", "entities": [[133, 143, "ORG"]]}, {"content": "And especially, as we were talking about ex-politicians, I would like to make a special call-out to Mr Lau Ping Sum who celebrates his 80th birthday today, in there interpreting for us from English to Chinese and vice versa.", "entities": [[100, 115, "PERSON"]]}]